<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrey Petrov</title>
    <link>https://shazow.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Andrey Petrov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:55:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://shazow.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner Sourdough: Does anything really matter?</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/beginner-sourdough-does-anything-really-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 21:55:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/beginner-sourdough-does-anything-really-matter/</guid>
      <description>There are bazillions of sourdough recipes in the wild, foaming with traffic from eager bakers trapped in quarantine, ready for their sourdough starter baby with a punny name to graduate into a tube of sustenance and distraction during dark times.
Sourdough recipes are more involved than regular bread recipes, that’s for sure. There are many steps, and bakers can’t seem to agree on many of them. That’s no accident, a great sourdough bake needs to be adjusted to our kitchen and our starter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open sourcing urllib3’s finances</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/open-sourcing-urllib3s-finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 21:13:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/open-sourcing-urllib3s-finances/</guid>
      <description>Since urllib3 was created in 2008, we have gained several amazing maintainers and hundreds of contributors. Any time you do anything that touches HTTP in Python, you’re probably using urllib3 behind the scenes. It is the 2nd most downloaded third-party Python package, after pip.
Tens of thousands of engineering hours were donated by people working on their own time, unpaid. The whole world benefited from these important donations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My computer is my home</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/my-computer-is-my-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 16:34:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/my-computer-is-my-home/</guid>
      <description>I spent fifty hours setting up my new computer, and I feel a mixture of shame and pride about it.
We spend a lot of our lives in our computers. Working, socializing, relaxing. On the work laptop, at the home desktop, on the phone in bed.
We live in our computers, and we do little things to make ourselves feel more at home in them — a little more cozy. We change the wallpaper, install some new apps, buy a pretty case and some stickers for the back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to hand over an Open Source project to a new maintainer</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/how-to-hand-over-an-open-source-project-to-a-new-maintainer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 13:16:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/how-to-hand-over-an-open-source-project-to-a-new-maintainer/</guid>
      <description>After maintaining a project for many years, maybe you’re no longer using it yourself? Or maybe you’re burned out from the grind? Or you can’t afford to allocate time to it? Maybe it’s time to pass it on to somebody else.
I feel like there is more to learn from failure stories than success stories, so let’s start with those.
What not to do I’ve handed over several projects before, and some didn’t go as well as I’d hoped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quitting Twitter… ish.</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/quitting-twitter-ish/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 01:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/quitting-twitter-ish/</guid>
      <description>It has been over two months and I feel better.   My first tweet.
 I haven’t tweeted in over two months.
This is very unusual for me. I’ve been an avid tweeter since 2007. Writing tweets has become a part of my identity to the point where most my bios mention that I’m a tweet ghostwriter—composing and editing tweets for friends is one of my favourite things to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code boilerplate: Is it always bad?</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/code-boilerplate-is-it-always-bad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 16:47:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/code-boilerplate-is-it-always-bad/</guid>
      <description>A case study between Python and Go. In Go, a common complaint from newly-minted gophers who come from another language is the error handling pattern: result, err := DoSomething() if err != nil { return nil, err }``another, err := SomethingElse(result) if err != nil { return nil, err }``// We can be a bit more terse if we don&amp;amp;#39;t need to save any // variables outside of the if-scope: if err := MoreWork(another); err !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing a new master password</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/choosing-a-new-master-password/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 16:35:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/choosing-a-new-master-password/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been meaning to change and improve my master password for years. I knew the steps but I really wanted someone to spell it out for me anyways, so I’ll spell out the concrete steps for you.
Photo by Cristina Gottardi
Popular password managers work by maintaining an encrypted database of many secrets, protected by a combination of the master password and access to the encrypted database file that is synchronized across your devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neither self nor this: Receivers in Go</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/receivers-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 17:49:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/receivers-in-go/</guid>
      <description>Neither self nor this: Receivers in Go When getting started with Go, there is a strong temptation to bring baggage from your previous language. It’s a heuristic which is usually helpful, but sometimes counter-productive and inevitably results in regret.
Go does not have classes and objects, but it does have types that we can make many instances of. Further, we can attach methods to these types and they kind-of start looking like the classes we’re used to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In VR, Would a Rose Smell Sweeter?</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/in-vr-would-a-rose-smell-sweeter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 20:40:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/in-vr-would-a-rose-smell-sweeter/</guid>
      <description>In a few months, the first iteration of modern consumer virtual reality headsets are going to start shipping. A lot is rapidly changing and new applications are being discovered every week.
I present three stories that use VR technology to push our crafts beyond what was possible. Each story is focused around an amazing short video that is very much worth watching.
“This is not why I became an actor.” On the set of The Hobbit, Sir Ian McKellen broke down in tears after hours of delivering his lines as Gandalf to a handful of photographs floating amidst a sea of green.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I design JSON API responses</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/how-i-design-json-api-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 21:34:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/how-i-design-json-api-responses/</guid>
      <description>The goal of designing a public API response layout is to balance ease of use for consumers with commitment of stability from the provider. We can bolt on all kinds of crazy metadata and embedded values that we’ll regret having to maintain years later, like complex pagination schemes that don’t scale for evolving domain spaces or when we’re finally Web Scale and wasting millions on extra bandwidth from that emoji soup we thought would be hilarious to wrap each entry with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why aren’t we using SSH for everything?</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/ssh-how-does-it-even/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2015 20:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/ssh-how-does-it-even/</guid>
      <description>SSH, how does it even?
A few weeks ago, I wrote ssh-chat.
ssh http://t.co/E7Ilc0B0BC pic.twitter.com/CqYBR1WYO4
&amp;mdash; Andrey 🦃 Petrov (@shazow) December 13, 2014  The idea is simple: You open your terminal and type, $ ssh chat.shazow.net
Unlike many others, you might stop yourself before typing “ls” and notice — that’s no shell, it’s a chat room!
While the little details sink in, it dawns on you that there is something extra-special going on in here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urllib3, Stripe, and Open Source Grants</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/urllib3-stripe-and-open-source-grants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 21:01:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/urllib3-stripe-and-open-source-grants/</guid>
      <description>Urllib3, Stripe, and Open Source Grants Helping the future come a little soonerSix years ago, I built a better Python http library. It had then-novel things like connection pooling, thread-safety, multipart encoding, and more. Today, every Python user depends on it. Maintaining something for six years on my own time is not easy, even with a slew of coping strategies. A few hours here and there, every week, and slowly it chugs along—largely thanks to contributors undertaking the bigger tasks that I can’t knock off in a quick afternoon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Re: Facebook acquires Oculus</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/re-facebook-acquires-oculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 03:37:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/re-facebook-acquires-oculus/</guid>
      <description>Re: Facebook acquires Oculus A letter of concernHello, John Carmack.   https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/449594006217842688
   https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/449594072244568064
   https://twitter.com/ID_AA_Carmack/status/449594122936922112
 Thank you for being open to public discourse.
I am a passionate believer in the importance and imminence of virtual reality’s effects on our society. I was devastated when I read the news about Facebook acquiring OculusVR, and this is why:
Ecosystem The Oculus Rift was more than a timely piece of clever technology—it was a powerful rallying cry to which hundreds of developers and manufacturers answered the call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is your fantasy?</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/what-is-your-fantasy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 01:34:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/what-is-your-fantasy/</guid>
      <description>What is your fantasy? Finding the North Star for your career Dan Satterfield via Stellarium What do I really want? I’ve been thinking about this for many years.
Do I want to build a venture capital funded startup? A sustainable humble life-style business? An innovative independent game studio? A wildly-profitable consulting enterprise? Perhaps follow in the foot-steps of 37Signals, Github, Twitter, or Google?
Or maybe I would be happy working for somebody else but I just haven’t found the right place?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to maintain a successful open source project</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/posts/how-to-maintain-a-successful-open-source-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2013 21:47:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/posts/how-to-maintain-a-successful-open-source-project/</guid>
      <description>Excerpt from README.rst
How to maintain a successful open source project Lessons learned from five years of maintaining one of the most-used Python libraries. I’ve published dozens of open source projects over the years, mostly in Python and JavaScript. Few are old and stable, others are new and immature, some are wildly popular with a constant stream of contributors, but most linger until one day a trickle of users suddenly discover them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laser Eye Surgery</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/laser-eyes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 21:24:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/laser-eyes/</guid>
      <description>Laser Eye Surgery &amp;ldquo;What was it like?&amp;rdquo; More than anything else, it was creepy.
&amp;hellip; But worth it.
Bespectacled My first vision correction was prescribed in the midst of my high school years. I could see well enough to get around but with great effort and strain. By the time I got home from school, I had to take a long nap just to make it through the rest of the day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considering job offers? A checklist in alphabetical order</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/checklist-for-considering-job-offers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 17:38:28 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/checklist-for-considering-job-offers/</guid>
      <description>Considering job offers? A checklist in alphabetical order Every offer you get will include some details and omit others. To perform a proper comparison between multiple offers and reach a good decision, you&amp;rsquo;ll need all the details for all offers. After numerous back-and-forths with several companies, I composed a checklist ideal for anyone on the verge of deciding the next stage of their career.
 Benefits: Medical, dental, vision. Yes, you&amp;rsquo;re young and healthy, but root canals are much more painful when you&amp;rsquo;re paying for them out of your pocket.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List of must-have apps on OSX</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/list-of-must-have-apps-on-osx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2011 14:13:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/list-of-must-have-apps-on-osx/</guid>
      <description>List of must-have apps on OSX Or, first things I install when I nest into a fresh Apple computing device:
 Adium Chrome Firefox Clyppan Colloquy Dropbox Growl Homebrew Fink MacPorts MacVim (via Homebrew!) Notifyapp Google Notifier Pandoraboy Quicksilver Skype iTerm2 TotalTerminal Visor Transmission VLC Virtualbox XCode  (Based on my older post, New Macbook Pro, list of things I installed. What am I missing?)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Management Utilities</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/password-management-utilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 19:26:20 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/password-management-utilities/</guid>
      <description>Password Management Utilities We live in a time when cleartext usernames and passwords are leaked on a daily basis. In the last couple of months my accounts got compromised on Gawker, Sony, and MtGox. I decided it&amp;rsquo;s time to start using the one-password-per-service technique. These are tools I found in my research.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently using SuperGenPass, but considering writing my own version that uses customizeable multipass sha512, more symbol breadth in passwords, and some other improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbitrarily-Structured Data in Relational Databases</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/arbitrarily-structured-data-in-rdbms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 16:01:53 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/arbitrarily-structured-data-in-rdbms/</guid>
      <description>Arbitrarily-Structured Data in Relational Databases This approach is similar to FriendFeed&amp;rsquo;s schemaless database framework. The key difference is in the data locality.
The goal is not to build an effective schemaless database on top of a relational database, but rather to accomodate for rapidly-evolving relational schemas and reducing the difficult of migrating forward.
Hypothesis In an evolving relational (SQL) database schema, we store two types of data: Data we will be querying against and data we will be displaying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rules of thumb for novice designers (like myself)</title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/rules-of-thumb-for-novice-designers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2010 15:39:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/rules-of-thumb-for-novice-designers/</guid>
      <description>Rules of thumb for novice designers (like myself) My strategy as a novice designer is to keep track of some rules of thumb to reduce the probability of making bad mistakes from lack of experience. If I&amp;rsquo;m careful enough, then I can often get to a point where just a little polish from an experienced designer is what it takes to get it from the 80% to the 100% mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://shazow.net/everything/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shazow.net/everything/readme/</guid>
      <description>Everything Not Chronological This is a repository for my knowledge and thoughts about everything that is not time-sensitive.
Blog posts I need to port to this repository  Protip for ambitious engineers looking for a cool job: Forget job boards, talk to angel investors. Considering offers? A checklist in alphabetical order Circadian Somersault: 28 hour days for 1 week Invention: Pass-through multi-car elevators Why I Love Linux, also Part 2 What it&amp;rsquo;s like to stutter Apartment Hunting: Tips, tricks, and strategy  Things I should write about more  Salary Negotiation  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>